Sumith Sunil Pevekar

213-561-8743
pevekar@usc.edu in sumithpevekar
Los Angeles, CA 90007

University of Southern California's student enrolled in computer science with 2 years of experience in computer programming and data science. Seeking to leverage software development skills and forecasting abilities to become a software engineer at a reputed firm.

Education

University of Southern California

Master of Science in Computer Science

Vidyalankar Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering. GPA: 9.53/10.00

August 2022-May 2024

Los Angeles, USA July 2018-July 2022

Mumbai, India

Mumbai, India

Experience

Department of Computer Engineering, VIT

June 2021-August 2021

Machine Learning Intern

• Utilized analytical and technical expertise to deliver insights and suggestions for department's progress.

- Devised the "Applicant Eligibility System" for the department with 93.5% precision that takes the applicant's profile as an input and predicts whether an applicant will get hired or not along with the salary a person might receive after getting placed in a company.
- Performed data analysis to find that placement of candidates was highly correlated with academic qualification as well as experience of that candidate in that field.

Virtually Testing Foundation

January 2021-March 2021

Los Angeles, United States

Cybersecurity Intern

• Acquired practical knowledge and hands-on experience with virtual machines.

• Updated and launched firewall policies, and overall network security using VMware's "Hands-On Labs" portal.

PackBagbuddy LLP

December 2020-February 2021

Web Development Intern

Ahmedabad, India

- Analyzed bugs in the original website and created new database schema for the same running website.
- Developed Firebase based database model to improve the website performance.

Cloud Counselage Limited

March 2020, June 2020-July 2020

Web Development Intern

Mumbai, India

- Developed a chatbot which answers all the queries of the interns recruited by the company.
- The chatbot saved intern's as well as company's time as it answers all the queries instantly.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, JavaScript

Frameworks: Keras, Tensorflow, NLTK, OpenCV, Spacy, Scikit-learn, Pandas

Tools:Git, Postman Cloud Platforms: AWS

Projects

Consumer Purchase Intention Detector | Python, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing

• Developed SVM and LSTM based models to find the purchase intention of the customer towards a product using Twitter tweets. The model achieved an overall average accuracy of 76.9%.

Text Auto Correct | Python, Natural Language Processing

• The model finds the best match for the incorrect word and returns the 5 most similar words ordered by similarity and probability. The similar words are sorted according to Jaccard distance.

Heart Disease Prediction System | Python, Computer Vision, Signal Processing

• Created a Logistic Regression model with 81.96% performance which uses features such as maximum heart rate, resting blood pressure, cholesterol, gender, and age to determine if a person has heart disease or not.

Publications Google Scholar

- Sumith Pevekar, Aayush Pandey, Naresh Alwala, Prof. Prakash Parmar. 'A Machine Learning based Approach for Determining Consumer Purchase Intention using Tweets', 2021. International Journal of Engineering Research Technology
- Sumith Pevekar. 'Forecasting INR Exchange Rate Against USD, GBP, JPY, SGD, EUR, AED using Machine Learning', 2021. EPRA International Journal of Research Development (IJRD).